<resources>
    <string name="app_name">ScrollViewDemo</string>
    <string name= "heading">Royal University of Bhutan</string>
    <string name= "subheading">Gyalpozhing College of Information Technology</string>
    <string name= "info">The Gyalposhing College of Information Technology, officially inaugurated on 6th October, 2017 is one of the integral colleges of the Royal University of Bhutan.
        The decision to establish Gyalpozhing College of Information Technology was made during the meeting held on February 2, 2017 at the Hon’ble Prime Minister’s Office.
        In line with the decision, the chairman of Tertiary Education Board issued an executive order no. Ref No. MoE/EO/2017/4513 dated 20 February 2017 to establish the College.
        The institute is 24 kilometers away from Mongar town stretching an area of 62 acres of land engulfed by lush green mountains.
        The university is one of the three new colleges established in Eastern Bhutan with the VISION to be the ‘Center of Excellence in information Technology steeped in GNH values’.
        The college at its initial stage offers undergraduate programme in Bachelors of computer applications.
        The programme is taught by qualified and dedicated local and expatriate faculties.The methodology of “Learning by Doing” is a unique one adopted by GCIT.
        It aims at giving hands- on experience which helps the students understand the practical implementation aspects and the concepts associated with it.
        Furthermore, the collegeaims to diversify the programmes by including more practical and job-oriented coursein the long-run.
        The college now offers Bachelor of Science (BSc.) in Computer Science and Bachelor of Science in Information Technology along with the bachelor of computer application which was started when the college opened in 2017. While the BSc. IT is an entirely new programme, the BSc. Computer Science course has been moved from Sherubtse College in Trashigang.

The duration of the BSc. Computer Science programme at Gyalposhing College will now be four years instead of three as in the past.
        Currently, there are forty-one students pursuing this undergraduate programme.
        Meanwhile the BSc. IT is an entirely new programme started this year. The college admitted sixty-six students under this programme.
        BSc. IT, the graduates are being targeted to become a programmer and they will be more into gearing towards programming skills.
        And then when it comes to BSc. Computer Science programme, they will be a little bit into theory basis courses.
        They will be able to contribute towards the computer system analyst; software project manager and they will be able to do computer system designs,”
        said Tshering, Dean of Academic Affairs, Gyalposhing College of Information Technology, Monggar.

The management says the college has also been well equipped with all the needed resources to start the new programmes.
        Although Gyalpozhing College has a different teaching method from other institutes called learning by doing, the college couldn’t apply this method to the two new programmes.
        This teaching approach is a nonconventional method, which requires more effort from students to develop their own skills and knowledge.

“Unfortunately for this first cohort, the first semester was not able to start with this pedagogy because the University quality control division has given few more
        time to improve the materials because since this is new to the university system. So the material that we have proposed has been not up to the mark of university
        quality control division,” He added.

He further added that the college will present the materials on learning by doing by December this year. And if the university approves it, the college is expected to adopt
        the learning by doing teaching approach with BSc. IT from February next year. Meanwhile, the BSc. Computer Science programme will be taught in the conventional
        way as instructed by the Royal University of Bhutan. The college currently has more than two hundred fifty students and twelve teaching staff.
    </string>

</resources>